Elizabeth told Ted Faro she was headed for a place called US Robot Command.
To tell people about zero Don place still exists is a ruin
the us or I'm calling the Grey Ford Grave Horde.
Cherry name.
You'll find it in the Eastern Mountains buried under the tangled coils of a middle devil or a bor.
Seven Horace references were learning to call them.
I'll contact you when you get there.
I can't wait
The eclipse.
I'm not showing any.
Focus is at that location.
Shouldn't be anything you can't handle on your own.
Carry on.
Thanks.
On my own.
All right?
No.
Yeah.
Got their attention?
No.
The grave court and the shadow of a metal devil.
Great.
Okay,
I'm going in.
That's right.
That does it.
Time to take a look around the room.
Operation Enduring Victory.
What does that mean?
Whatever it was doesn't seem to have turned out very well.
Wait.
That's with defence is still on approach
live.
We got no mobility in here.
Punched right through us.
Battle frozen in ice time
Looks like quite And during victory, we put our foot in today contact in 30 seconds.
Okay.
I think That's enough time for so back to finish.
Zero Dawn.
If this is really it, I got to say it's been an honour to serve beside these tanks.
Here it comes.
Greece
getting this silence.
Silence!
Title inbound.
Same players, Accurate Based.
A fan slug!
Sit down!
Way engaged!
The lens blessed up France!
Silence!
You getting this?
What is it?
All these soldiers.
They died here.
People die all the time.
Keep going and find something interesting
stocking up
you.
It must have been where the soldiers slept.
Like the lodge and mother's heart, I guess.
Look, third Battle of California Marine.
The storm came in from the Pacific.
I don't know if it was.
The local Minutemen are crazy.
15th.
But they said the garbage patch away,
see, was on fire.
That stuff was
the first wave of butts came in, covered in burning sludge.
I bought us an hour to of slaughtering them on the beaches before the swarm recalculated.
We pulled the men, went back to the Kalmar sprawl, dropped buildings on them.
E impede the grid standard operating procedure.
The last time I was in California, I was five safe.
The light was like that vintage social net philtre that was everywhere in the forties.
Look,
first battle of the Eastern Seaboard wall.
A long run up to it.
This was before Kalmar and projections were a lot worse for the East.
For three weeks, we kept getting scrambled out to some coastal birds.
Train Minutemen.
It was raining on account of Europe already being torched.
Block after block of prefab barracks.
They were still printing barracks right up into the hour.
The main force hit the minute man.
We ran combat drills with them in the streets where they lived, trying to pretend they might live to die somewhere else if they paid attention.
Nothing worse than the ones who actually bought into it.
Hopeful, pestering us with questions about zero dawn like we know something they don't.
This where the more we do this, the more like the bots we are.
Except they learned from every fight.
Yes, I'm not so sure.
What was this place
recalls?
I've been instructed to remind you of Article 115 of base policy regarding unauthorised use of processor cycles.
Specifically, 115 See any holographic simulation not directly related to operational training or efficiency consider yourself reminded and enjoy a gaming.
Thanks for the males.
You
time goes fast.
Elected duty.
Four months for the record recalls.
I don't know.
20 Drops in and out of the West Coast fighting with the civilian and this He's scrappy guys and gals.
Their training is basically here's a D w when you see it but it
But somehow it's all coming together between us and the six time R B.
We took down a horse and lithium beach, pulled out before his buddies arrived.
But big won't go down.
I hope you make the news.
Showed everyone we're gonna have just turning this around.
We just need to give projects they rode on the time it needs.
Everything will be the way it used to be.
I know it's been days, honey.
I'm sorry.
Deployments Getting real long and tougher every time.
Swarms getting better, protecting us less of us now.
And we have to put in 10 times the work for everyone Gone like a family business on hard times on me.
This isn't my family.
Stop with you.
I still try to see you.
The life we had in the eyes of the people out there.
I remember when they were glad to see us when they still had a home.
It also slipping away.
I recognise the places we're defending.
The only thing I know I'm still fighting for is
you.
Because you're gone to turn this around, whatever the hell that is.
The furnishings were metal.
How'd they ever get comfortable?
It was the metal world.
Yes, they were used to it.
Looking back, I thought 64 was shaping up to be a pretty good year.
No more drinking and no more mercenary sec work stripping offshore wind farms for the Oh, easy.
Just me in a plasma cutter 400 ft above sea level.
Then I got the recall alert.
Read them up on a turbine in the smell of cooking ozone.
They covered every angle.
Better pay amnesty for any combined wars.
You fought in guaranteed citizenship.
We should have thought.
Okay, what's the catch?
But what we did think was I guess we're better than the box after all.
Big talk from Harris about pride and duty.
Smart guy.
He was right.
I've been proud to be a U.
S.
Soldier.
I jumped at the chance to be one again.
And look what I landed.
In.
Who?
Just one bed.
Maybe they're war Chiefs Room.
Last night we got talking about D Day 55.
I was a kid then on ly a few years out of boot camp General Assembly and a drone hangar Summer and the sky was bear.
The heat was killer.
They say US human combat forces air being disbanded, All automated.
Now we're last cycle's tech out like the old net.
A million more on basic in a century recession could be you'll help build the robots that took your jobs.
Or if you know how to handle a power suit, you could find a place that still uses manual labour.
Maybe a neo easy or China, where you're not our problem.
A low suicide risk.
It said in my discharge file
Red light.
I guess that means no power.
These wires must run to the power source.
Whatever power this door should be close by.
Holographic interface must be some kind of code.
Maybe I should try scanning objects in this area.
Well, that's informative.
Three power lines sources.
That makes one
Me.
Hey, you wanted to know.
I remember the geothermal system reboot.
It goes like this.
Bird flies north and summer, East spring, West falls south in winter.
I didn't expect to hear nature's free from the lips of, like, the TT technology idea.
As usual, I defy expectations.
Two more.
Okay, that did.
Sounds like that.
Did it
to be used on viruses, clips,
another power cell.
This should help me get to that ancient armour.
Okay.
Like
it's them.
All right?
They're not looking for answers.
Just
got it right.
Yeah.
Keep quiet now.
I'd have to ditch something.
Forget about travelling light.
Thank you.
Dig.
Thanks for the males.
You
Time goes fast on active duty.
Four months with the wrecking recalls fighting with the civilian in this daze.
Scrappy guys and girls, that's all coming together between us and the sixth m r B wheat down the horse.
I hope you made the news.
Honey showed everyone one turning this around.
We just need to give projects.
There were gone the time it needs.
I know it's been days, honey.
I'm sorry.
Deployments
getting real long.
We have to put him to work for everyone.
Like a family business.
I still see you in the eyes of the people out there.
They were glad to see us.
They still had hope.
I'm still fighting for you.
Status Report ninth Mechanised Response Brigade Commanding Officer Lieutenant Fiona Morale Unit Morale continues to be adversely impacted by outbound engagements against the Pharaoh plague, especially when said engagements occur in sectors where civilian guard in less D's have bean heavily engaged the scope and nature of fatalities suffered by civilian garden unarmed civilians in these sectors defy description, and witnessing it is generating a pervasive sense of hopelessness in the unit.
Accordingly, I once again requests that deployments of the ninth M R B be temporarily refocused on facilities that a mission critical to Project Zero Dawn.
And once again, I request an immediate update on the status of Project zero Dawn's Timeline.
Ames.
I don't even know if you're alive anymore.
The males I get from you, they say they're from you, but they don't sound.
They sound recycled phrases put together, and you don't say anything about the news.
I pass on the containment zone.
The re breather is the rioting one Earth.
What happened in the Dallas bubble aims.
That wasn't the robots.
They won't even give me a straight answer when I demand to know if you're still alive.
They just say, If your messages keep coming, then you're still operational.
It is not fair aims.
It's not fair that you won't be with me when the lights go out for you.
That's so sad,
Ames.
I know email you too much.
I'm just proud of what you're doing.
Everyone back home is we got moved in last 10 kilometres just as a precaution.
They say school's still in session.
So I get to keep my eye on Andreas and Reggie.
We never know where when you're fighting But when the Beatles go over, all the kids run out and wave.
I believe in you.
I knew nothing's ever gonna be the same But I believe in you I believe in us.
December 2065 Week one Confidential Operation Kickback Reno, Nevada Civilian garden Armour Battalion skirmished with Vanguard Elements of Pacific Northwest swarm PM 12 Engagement began at 600 concluded with a withdrawal a 21 100 the following day Losses in excess of 40% reported Operation Fix Go Shenandoah Valley Tech, Virginia 12th m r.
Be supported by civilian guard Fatah rearguard action against the Eastern Seaboard swarming yes 17.
Engagement began at 800 at approximately 1400 12th.
MRV reported the position was overrun and received authorisation to detonate Test a tech facility, inflicting significant damage on the S 17.
Surviving elements of the 12th MRV withdrawn to Akron Cleveland Defensive line Operation Body Blow, Akron, Ohio Ninth and 10th M Arby's, supported by sustained aerial strikes.
Assaulted the Horace Class Titan resupplying the Eastern Seaboard.
Swarm E s 18 Engagement began it 0 400 concluded a 22 100 with the elimination of the Titan.
Note that this is nine m Arby's third Titan kill with minimal losses.
Brigade readiness status third Ammar be refused Recall orders from Operation Pinch hit deployment along Pensacola Tallahassee Defensive line Court martial proceedings underway.
Seventh M R.
Be recalled from New York engagement Zone to reinforce Wichita Theatre.
Ready ninth M R B refitting at U.
S.
R.
C.
Facilities ready.
10th.
Ammar be transferred from Kalmar.
Data corrupted
Full Already
you told.
What is this?
That it's a mess.
A map of what?
A world?
The planet Earth alloy.
It's not fled like you thought.
Why would I think that during eclipses, the shadow cast on the moon is curved.
So how old is a globe?
It looks like this from a distance.
We'll discuss this another time.
Back to the meadow hand, the Faro robots were spreading across the world, eating everything up.
Somehow, Elizabeth stopped them before it was too late.
But how?
The eclipse?
They don't think they like it, do they?
Another polish on this one can move.
No way.
I had 500 of those once.
No,
I'll tuck that away.
I'll find a use for you.
I can't spare the weight
Mine now.
No
report.
Biosphere Degradation, August 2065.
Confidential chief findings Despite increased tactical proficiency of elite and civilian guard units and many hard won engagements in the central European, Antarctic and Pacific reached theatres, the pharaoh plagues rate of advance has not slowed, nor has its bio mass consumption rate.
Damage to the biosphere has already exceeded 2038 levels by every measure and grows worse by the day.
Extinction timeline projections remain unchanged, with a predicted for mid November 2065 annihilation of exposed human populations.
In February 2066 extinction of macrobiotic land organisms by the end of March 2066 and extinction of marine life in early 2068.
Continued secrecy Re Project zero Don.
The utter silence regarding its mechanisms of action and completion date make it impossible to predict zero Dawn's impact or lack of impact on the extinction.
Timeline.
Atmospheric collapse, atmospheric oxygen depletion and toxic emissions remain the greatest environmental threat to operation and during victory, as well as the wider civilian population and animal life.
Operational Atmospheric collapse
is currently predicted for mid November 2065 after which military personnel will require we're breathing apparatuses to operate in the open and civilians will only be able to survive inside sealed structures.
The requirements for air scrubbing and recycling and facilities is addressed in addendum.
A link to this report.
Potable Water Shortages Major water treatment facilities are already struggling to process.
Water source is compromised by rainfall heavily contaminated by toxins emitted by the consumption of the Eastern Hemisphere.
Following the necessary shutdown of all nano scrubbing functionality, Wastewater recycling is already beyond capacity.
Military response escalation, A dental linked to this document cover the short term effects of scorched earth engagements in defence of the Western Seaboard in the ongoing effects of the oceanic economic sounds use of nuclear weapons to delay the enemy's initial advance across the Pacific Theatre.
David Corrupted.
Thank you, Dr Silva.
You can take a seat.
You're going to psych her after what she just said.
Dr.
Sobek has made the situation very clear, General, and given us an option we should all be thanking here.
That's just I mean, my God, maybe take this discussion off line.
There's not going to be any discussion.
You saw the numbers, that Pharaoh, he will foot the bill, but his money can't buy the time necessary to complete zero dawn.
That's
that will be paid for in blood.
Oh, come on.
If we upgrade our fleet cracked the code somehow.
Were you not listening?
Robots can't do the fighting for you this time.
When it comes to hacking, this rogue swarm is an apex predator.
Anything automated you throw at it, they will hijack and takeover.
But thiss we'll be throwing civilians into a meat grinder.
Commanders, the enemy.
We're facing self replicates faster than we can kill it.
And it eats biomass as fuel zero Dawn is all we've got.
So we put a rail gun in the hand of every civilian is strong enough to carry one.
Show them where the trigger is and point them to the front.
How the hell did we sell that?
By giving them something to fight for.
Zeroed on the top secret super weapons programme that will save us so long as humanity holds up the swarm long enough for doctors so back and her team to finish it.
The file I'm sending contains the war plan for Operation Enduring Victory War Plan.
This is a war crime.
It may be ugly, but it's something.
Consider the alternative
not to so bad.
I've secured use of a decommissioned orbital launch base outside Bryce.
Utah has zero don staging area.
Plenty of space there.
When can you get started?
I have already mailed you a list of Alfa and Beta candidates.
Most are foreign nationals or subjects of corporate holdings.
So extracting them Leave that to me.
You'll get your dream team Kanta.
Then I'll be off
a little long chase.
What is that?
What did these people?
D'oh!
What did Elizabeth d'oh!
I have to leave something else behind.
Doctor so back as projected, the Wichita salient has collapsed.
Five Horace class titans have broken through.
We predict contact in 34 hours.
Everything is in position, General.
It took a few shortcuts to pull everything together.
But
zero dawn is functionally complete.
Good to go.
Enduring victory Served its purpose after all.
Yes, If we'd had even one day less.
I've sent you an encoded file.
Doctor, please do me the favour of archiving.
Oh, I'll see what I can do.
What is it?
A brief statement.
Allocution with crimes.
I guess you'd call it.
So what are you admitting?
Guilt?
Over the past 16 months, Doctor, I have presided over the greatest wholesale slaughter of military person now and civilians in the history of
history.
Genghis Khan, Hitler style and Sora Bella Adam altogether.
They don't even come close.
You didn't do the killing, general.
No, not the ring.
But I didn't wind up the eyes rank military commander in the United States by resisting the automation of the armed forces.
Even before the swarm Doctor, I was helping death alone.
So instead of letting what I've done sink into the murk, I forgot
I sent a file with all the details that posterity judge my actions with clear vision.
I'll do as you ask, General, but you should consider that.
Were it not for your actions, our actions, there wouldn't be any posterity to judge us.
Perhaps not just so big.
How do you say general
and goodbye?
Hell of a thing.
Glad to be rid of that place.
Now I just need to find the orbital launch base they talked about.
I've checked my data and looking to the base.
That's the good news
and the bad.
It's directly underneath the Citadel, the palace.
It's sinful.
The capital of the Shadow Kharja.
Not exactly convenience.
The palace is crawling with eclipse agents, many in positions of authority.
All of them wearing focuses the moment they see you.
Haiti's will to heal issue another kill order, and this time the entire Shadow Kharja military will be after you so disabled.
Their focus is you've done it before.
It's not that simple.
Too many focuses in one place, each of them communicating with each other and back to Haiti's, A whole network of them network.
What's that?
Imagine a vast, invisible web stretched across the land from end to end connecting focuses together, allowing them to communicate over vast distances instantaneously.
All right, so is there some way to cut the web down?
Crash The network.
Audacious years There is a way, a weak point in the network, by the way.
I'll send the location data to your focus head there, and I'll be in touch when you're close with more directions.
What was zero dawn sort of super weapon?
Does a bit make
machines fromthe world she knew for civilisation.
Let's come to that again.